Guide to the Joshua A. Fishman Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 17: Accession 2011-023
  - Subseries I: Geographic Designations
    - Countries: General (Carton 1, Folder 1)
    - Afghanistan (Carton 1, Folder 2)
    - Africa (Carton 1, Folder 3)
    - Alaska (Carton 1, Folder 4)
    - Alsace-Lorraine (Carton 1, Folder 5)
    - Ardennes (Carton 1, Folder 6)
    - Argentina (Carton 1, Folder 7)
    - Armenia (Carton 1, Folder 8)
    - Asia (Carton 1, Folder 9)
    - Australia (Carton 1, Folder 10)
    - Australia (Carton 1, Folder 11)
    - Australia (Carton 1, Folder 12)
    - Australia (Carton 1, Folder 13)
    - Austria-Hungary (Carton 1, Folder 14)
    - Azabadhan (Carton 1, Folder 15)
    - Bangladesh (Carton 1, Folder 16)
    - Basque autonomous region (Carton 1, Folder 17)
    - Belarus (Carton 1, Folder 18)
    - Benelux (Carton 1, Folder 19)
    - Belgium (Carton 1, Folder 20)
    - Bolzano-Bozen (Carton 1, Folder 21)
    - Brazil (Carton 1, Folder 22)
    - Brennero (Carton 1, Folder 23)
    - Brittany (Carton 1, Folder 24)
    - Bulgaria (Carton 1, Folder 25)
    - Bunderhaus (Carton 1, Folder 26)
    - Cambodia (Carton 1, Folder 27)
    - Cameroon (Carton 1, Folder 28)
    - Canada (Carton 1, Folder 29)
    - Canada (Carton 1, Folder 30)
    - Cantons (Carton 1, Folder 31)
    - Catalonia (Carton 1, Folder 32)
    - Catalonia (Carton 1, Folder 33)
    - Charlemagne (Carton 1, Folder 34)
    - Chile (Carton 1, Folder 35)
    - China (Carton 1, Folder 36)
    - Colombia (Carton 1, Folder 37)
    - Cyprus (Carton 1, Folder 38)
    - Denmark (Carton 1, Folder 39)
    - Dietsch (Carton 1, Folder 40)
    - Eastern Europe (Carton 1, Folder 41)
    - ECSC Treaty (Carton 1, Folder 42)
    - Ecuador (Carton 1, Folder 43)
    - England (Carton 1, Folder 44)
    - Estonia (Carton 1, Folder 45)
    - Ethiopia (Carton 1, Folder 46)
    - Fiji Islands (Carton 2, Folder 1)
    - Finland (Carton 2, Folder 2)
    - Flemish (Carton 2, Folder 3)
    - France (Carton 2, Folder 4)
    - Friesland (Carton 2, Folder 5)
    - Frisian (Carton 2, Folder 6)
    - German (Carton 2, Folder 7)
    - German (Carton 2, Folder 8)
    - Ghana (Carton 2, Folder 9)
    - Greece (Carton 2, Folder 10)
    - Guatamala (Carton 2, Folder 11)
    - Haiti (Carton 2, Folder 12)
    - Holy Roman Empire (Carton 2, Folder 13)
    - Hong Kong (Carton 2, Folder 14)
    - Hungary (Carton 2, Folder 15)
    - India (Carton 2, Folder 16)
    - India (Carton 2, Folder 17)
    - Indonesia (Carton 2, Folder 18)
    - Iraq (Carton 2, Folder 19)
    - Ireland (Carton 2, Folder 20)
    - Ireland (Carton 2, Folder 21)
    - Ireland (Carton 2, Folder 22)
    - Ireland (Carton 2, Folder 23)
    - Ireland (Carton 2, Folder 24)
    - Israel (Carton 2, Folder 25)
    - Israel (Carton 2, Folder 26)
    - Italy (Carton 2, Folder 27)
    - Japan, Kazakhstan, Kenya, Korea, Kosovo (Carton 2, Folder 28)
    - Ladin, Latin America, Latvia, Liechtenstein, Ligurian (Carton 2, Folder 29)
    - Low Countries, Luxembourg, Macedonia, Madagascar, Malaysia (Carton 2, Folder 30)
    - Mauritius, Mexico, Moldova, Monaco, Monegasque, Mongolia, Monte Carlo, Montenegro, Morocco (Carton 2, Folder 31)
    - Nepal, Netherland Antilles, New Zealand (Carton >3, Folder 1)
    - Nigeria, Pakistan, Paraguay, Peru, Philipines, Puerto Rico (Carton >3, Folder 2)
    - Quebec (Carton >3, Folder 3)
    - Rhine River Basin, Romania, Russia, Rwanda, St. Maarten, San Marino, Schengen Agreement (Carton >3, Folder 4)
    - Scotland (Carton >3, Folder 5)
    - Seborga, Serbia, Siberia, Singapore, Slovakia (Carton >3, Folder 6)
    - Slovenia, Small European countries, Solomon Islands (Carton >3, Folder 7)
    - South Africa, South Asia, South Tyrol, Soviet Union (former), Spain (Carton >3, Folder 8)
    - Sri Lanka, Strasbourg, Suriname, Sweden, Swiss Confederation (Carton >4, Folder 1)
    - Swiss German, Switzerland, Taiwan, Tanzania, Tatarstan (Carton >4, Folder 2)
    - Tavolara, Tibet, Tibetan Areas of China, Trentino, Trinidad (Carton >4, Folder 3)
    - Turkey, Turkmeniston, Uganda, Ukraine, United Arab Emirites (Carton >4, Folder 4)
    - USA, Uzbekistan, Valencia, Wales, West African Countries (Carton >4, Folder 5)
    - Western Europe, Wolof, World's Smallest Countries, Yugoslavia (Carton >4, Folder 6)
    - Zambia, Zimbabwe (Carton >4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II: Languages
    - Languages: General (Carton >5, Folder 1)
    - Audio CD: Theory of Languages (Carton >5, Folder 2)
    - Acadian, Afro-American, Afrikaans, Albanian (Carton >5, Folder 3)
    - Alsatian, Amazonian, American Sign Language, Amish, Angolan (Carton >5, Folder 4)
    - Arabic (Carton >5, Folder 5)
    - Arabic in Israel, Aramaic, Armenian, Asian Pacific Americans (Carton >5, Folder 6)
    - Asian Indians in America, Assyrian (Carton >5, Folder 7)
    - Asturian (Carton >5, Folder 8)
    - Australian Aboriginal, Azerbaijani, Baltic Languages (Carton >5, Folder 9)
    - Basque (Carton >6, Folder 1)
    - Basque (Carton >6, Folder 2)
    - Basque: Audio CD's (Carton >6, Folder 3)
    - Basque (Carton >6, Folder 4)
    - Basque (Carton >6, Folder 5)
    - Basque (Carton >6, Folder 6)
    - Basque: Audio Cassette (Carton >7, Folder 1)
    - Belarus, Belgium, Bengali, Berber, Bhoti (Carton >7, Folder 2)
    - Black English/Ebonics (Carton >7, Folder 3)
    - Breton (Carton >7, Folder 4)
    - Breton (Carton >7, Folder 5)
    - Cornish (Carton >7, Folder 6)
    - Cornish (Carton >7, Folder 7)
    - Cornish (Carton >8, Folder 1)
    - Cornish: Submission to Cornish Language Board Commission, March 2007 (Carton >8, Folder 2)
    - Cornish (Carton >8, Folder 3)
    - Cornish (Carton >8, Folder 4)
    - Cornish (Carton >8, Folder 5)
    - Cornish: Books (Carton >9, Folder 1)
    - Cornish: Books (Carton >9, Folder 2)
    - Cornish (Carton >9, Folder 3)
    - Cornish (Carton >9, Folder 4)
    - Cornish (Carton >9, Folder 5)
    - Cornish (Carton >9, Folder 6)
    - Caribbean region, Carpatho-Rusyn (Carton >10, Folder 1)
    - Catalan, Chamorro, Chinese (Carton >10, Folder 2)
    - Chinese (Carton >10, Folder 3)
    - Chuvash, Circassian, Creole (Carton >10, Folder 4)
    - Croatian (Carton >10, Folder 5)
    - Cuban in U.S.A. (Carton >10, Folder 6)
    - Czech (Carton >10, Folder 7)
    - Danish, Dungan, Dutch (Carton >10, Folder 8)
    - English (Carton >11, Folder 1)
    - English around the World, English in Great Britain (Carton >11, Folder 2)
    - English in U.S.A. (Carton >11, Folder 3)
    - English First, English Only, English Plus (Carton >11, Folder 4)
    - English in South Asia, Esperanto, Estonian (Carton >11, Folder 5)
    - Filipino, Filipino in Australia, Flemish, French (Carton >11, Folder 6)
    - French-Canada (Quebec), Frisian, Friulan (Carton >11, Folder 7)
    - Gaelic (Carton >12, Folder 1)
    - Gaelic (Carton >12, Folder 2)
    - Gaelic (Carton >12, Folder 3)
    - Gaelic (Carton >12, Folder 4)
    - Galician (Carton >12, Folder 5)
    - Gallego (Carton >12, Folder 6)
    - German (Carton >12, Folder 7)
    - German in U.S.A. (Carton >12, Folder 8)
    - Goa (Carton >12, Folder 9)
    - Greek (Carton >13, Folder 1)
    - Haitian in U.S.A. (Carton >13, Folder 2)
    - Hausa (Carton >13, Folder 3)
    - Hawaiian (Carton >13, Folder 4)
    - Hebrew (Carton >13, Folder 5)
    - Hebrew in the U.S.A. (Carton >13, Folder 6)
    - Hebrew Language Acacemy (Carton >13, Folder 7)
    - Hindi (Carton >13, Folder 8)
    - Hispanics in U.S.A. (Carton >13, Folder 9)
    - Hispanics in U.S.A. (Carton >13, Folder 10)
    - Hmong (Carton >13, Folder 11)
    - Hungarian (Carton >13, Folder 12)
    - Icelandic American (Carton >13, Folder 13)
    - Igbo (Carton >13, Folder 14)
    - Indonesian (Carton >13, Folder 15)
    - Inuit (Carton >13, Folder 16)
    - Inuktitut (Carton >13, Folder 17)
    - Irish (Carton >13, Folder 18)
    - Irish (Carton >14, Folder 1)
    - Israeli Arabic (Carton >14, Folder 2)
    - Italian (Carton >14, Folder 3)
    - Japanese (Carton >14, Folder 4)
    - Jewish Language: other than Yiddish (Carton >14, Folder 5)
    - Kannada (Carton >14, Folder 6)
    - Kannadigas (Carton >14, Folder 7)
    - Karuk (Carton >14, Folder 8)
    - Kazakh (Carton >14, Folder 9)
    - Kiswahili (Carton >14, Folder 10)
    - Klingon (Carton >14, Folder 11)
    - Korean in U.S.A. (Carton >14, Folder 12)
    - Kurdish (Carton >14, Folder 13)
    - Kyrgyz (Carton >14, Folder 14)
    - Ladin (Carton >14, Folder 15)
    - Ladino (Carton >14, Folder 16)
    - Latgalian (Carton >14, Folder 17)
    - Latin (Carton >14, Folder 18)
    - Latvian (Carton >14, Folder 19)
    - Lenape (Carton >14, Folder 20)
    - Livonian (Carton >14, Folder 21)
    - Macedonian (Carton >14, Folder 22)
    - Maidu (Carton >14, Folder 23)
    - Malay (Carton >14, Folder 24)
    - Malta (Carton >14, Folder 25)
    - Maori (Carton >14, Folder 26)
    - Marathi (Carton >14, Folder 27)
    - Maya (Carton >14, Folder 28)
    - Mexican in U.S.A. (Carton >15, Folder 1)
    - Mordvinian (Carton >15, Folder 2)
    - Maori (Maori Language Commission) (Carton >15, Folder 3)
    - Maori (videocassette) (Carton >15, Folder 4)
    - Maori (Carton >15, Folder 5)
    - Maori (Carton >15, Folder 6)
    - Maori (Carton >15, Folder 7)
    - Maori (Carton >15, Folder 8)
    - Maori (Carton >16, Folder 1)
    - Maori (Carton >16, Folder 2)
    - Maori (Carton >16, Folder 3)
    - Maori (Carton >16, Folder 4)
    - Maori (Carton >16, Folder 5)
    - Maori (Carton >16, Folder 6)
    - Maori (Carton >17, Folder 1)
    - Maori (Carton >17, Folder 2)
    - Maori (Carton >17, Folder 3)
    - Nahuatl (Carton >17, Folder 4)
    - Native American (Carton >17, Folder 5)
    - Native American (Carton >18, Folder 1)
    - Native American (Carton >18, Folder 2)
    - Native American (Carton >18, Folder 3)
    - Native American (Carton >18, Folder 4)
    - Navajo (Carton >18, Folder 5)
    - Navajo (Carton >19, Folder 1)
    - Nordic, Norwegian, Nubian, Ojibwe, Patwa (Carton >19, Folder 2)
    - Pilipino, Pipil, Piraha, Platdietsch (Mennonite German) (Carton >19, Folder 3)
    - Polish, Portugese, Provencal, Pulaar, Punjabi (Carton >19, Folder 4)
    - Quecha (Carton >19, Folder 5)
    - Romani, Romani-Jewish Alliance in U.S.A., Romansh (Carton >19, Folder 6)
    - Russian, Rusyn (Carton >19, Folder 7)
    - Sanskrit, Sardinian, Scots-Gailic, Serbo-Croatian (Carton >19, Folder 8)
    - Setswana, Setu, S-L topics (Sexist/Non-Sexist), Sinhala, Sino-Tibetan, Slovene (Carton >19, Folder 9)
    - Sorbian (Carton >20, Folder 1)
    - Spanglish (Carton >20, Folder 2)
    - Spanish in the U.S.A. (Carton >20, Folder 3)
    - Spanish (Carton >20, Folder 4)
    - Spanish (Carton >20, Folder 5)
    - Swahili (Carton >20, Folder 6)
    - Tai (Carton >20, Folder 7)
    - Tamil (Carton >20, Folder 8)
    - Teluga (Carton >20, Folder 9)
    - Thai in the U.S.A. (Carton >20, Folder 10)
    - Trinidadian English (Carton >20, Folder 11)
    - Turkish (Carton >20, Folder 12)
    - Ukranian (Carton >20, Folder 13)
    - Urdu (Carton >20, Folder 14)
    - Uyghur (Carton >20, Folder 15)
    - Valencia (Carton >20, Folder 16)
    - Vietnamese (Carton >21, Folder 1)
    - Voro (Carton >21, Folder 2)
    - Welsh (Carton >21, Folder 3)
    - Welsh (Carton >21, Folder 4)
    - Welsh (Carton >21, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish Worldwide (not in U.S.A. or Israel) (Carton >21, Folder 6)
    - Yiddish Worldwide (not in U.S.A. or Israel) (Carton >21, Folder 7)
    - Yiddish Worldwide (not in U.S.A. or Israel) (Carton >21, Folder 8)
    - Yiddish Worldwide (not in U.S.A. or Israel) (Carton >21, Folder 9)
    - Yiddish (Carton >22, Folder 1)
    - Yiddish (Carton >22, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish (Carton >22, Folder 3)
    - Yiddish - computer list, 2003 (Carton >22, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish (Carton >22, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish in Israel (Carton >22, Folder 6)
    - Yiddish in Israel (Carton >22, Folder 7)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. (Carton >23, Folder 1)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. (Carton >23, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. (Carton >23, Folder 3)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. (Carton >23, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. (Carton >23, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. - Michoel Ronn (Carton >23, Folder 6)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. - Secularist (Carton >23, Folder 7)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. (Carton >23, Folder 8)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. - 2007 (Carton >24, Folder 1)
    - Yiddish in U.S.A. - 2007 (Carton >24, Folder 2)
    - Yiddish (Khasidim) (Carton >24, Folder 3)
    - Yinglish (Carton >24, Folder 4)
    - Yiddish/Hebrew and other Jewish languages (Carton >24, Folder 5)
    - Yiddish/Hebrew and other Jewish languages (Carton >24, Folder 6)
    - Yoruba (Carton >24, Folder 7)
  - Subseries III: Sociolinguistic Topics
    - Advertising/Bilingual Education (Carton >24, Folder 8)
    - Birth and Death of a Language (Carton >24, Folder 9)
    - Child Language, Chomskyanism, Computer Language Info., Contact Linguistics, The Deaf (Carton >25, Folder 1)
    - Dictionaries, Education (Carton >25, Folder 2)
    - Endangered, Disappearing, Threatened languages (Carton >25, Folder 3)
    - English Language debate, European Union, Folk Linguistics (Carton >25, Folder 4)
    - Fusian Languages, Globalization, Immigrant Language Retention/Suppression, Languages and Dialects (Carton >25, Folder 5)
    - Language and Film, Language and Healthcare, Language and the Law (Carton >25, Folder 6)
    - Language and Nationalism, Language and Radio, Language and Religion, Language and Science (Carton >25, Folder 7)
    - Language and TV, Writing Systems, Language Academics, Accents, Language Archives (Carton >26, Folder 1)
    - Language Cartoons, Language Change, Language History, Language in Translation (Carton >26, Folder 2)
    - Language Maintenance and Shift, Language Policy, Language Preservation (Carton >26, Folder 3)
    - Language Scholar's Obituaries (Carton >26, Folder 4)
    - Linguistic Diversity, Linguistic Purism (Carton >26, Folder 5)
    - Maps, Minority Education, Minority Language, Multilingualism (Carton >26, Folder 6)
    - Orthography, Politeness Studies, Research Network on Language Policy, Racism (Carton >26, Folder 7)
    - Sociolinguistics, Scholars in the Field (Carton >26, Folder 8)
    - Speaking in Tongues, Stateless Nations, Street Slang, Surnames, Xenoglossophobia (Carton >26, Folder 9)
  - Subseries IV: JAF Expert Witness at Trial Pertaining to a Francaphone "Bilingualism Issue" in Alberta Canada, 2006-2008
    - Descriptions of the Trial (Carton >26, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Carton >27, Folder 1)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >27, Folder 2)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >27, Folder 3)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >28, Folder 1)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >28, Folder 2)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >28, Folder 3)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >28, Folder 4)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >28, Folder 5)
    - Informative Documents for JAF testimony (Carton >28, Folder 6)
    - Trial proceeding in English and French (Carton >29, Folder 1)
    - JAF Reply Testimony (Carton >29, Folder 2)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >29, Folder 3)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >29, Folder 4)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >29, Folder 5)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >30, Folder 1)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >30, Folder 2)
    - Testimony of other witnesses and Dr. Landry (Carton >30, Folder 3)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >30, Folder 4)
    - Testimony of other witnesses (Carton >30, Folder 5)
    - Invoices and travel information (Carton >30, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous posters (Carton >31)
    - Proposal for Eugene and Estelle Ferkauf: to name the Graduate School of Education of Yeshiva University (Carton >32)